Alon Avramson

054-4787592 | alon1122@gmail.com | Petach Tikva | https://www.linkedin.com/in/alonavramson/ 

Target: With huge cross-functional management experience, Seeking Director of Product role in AI-driven B2B platforms where innovation, execution, and cross-functional leadership drive business growth.

Executive Summary

Strategic product management leader with 20+ years of experience in launching innovative AI/ML, IoT, Cloud, Video, and Automotive solutions. Proven expertise in driving business growth, leading cross-functional teams, and delivering cutting-edge products for global clients.

A creator with entrepreneurial spirit, Initiated and led new products from idea to sales for customers: Automotive/Utilities/TV Operators/ProAV/ IT/Music/Defense/Integrators/Traders. B2B, B2C, B2B2C, B2D

Business changes: first product in a startup (Business Layers), second product in a startup (Midbartech), large project with T-1 US (Bigband) from devices to systems and system as a product (Scopus), a blue ocean (Visonic) from appliances to software products (Kremer), from on-prem to cloud (mPrest), entrepreneurial (Cycles-Trader), established a new domain AI/ML (RedBend / Harman)

Main Achievements 
Identifying the next major business opportunity, translate it to products, generating multi-millions-dollars.

Professional Experience

Senior AI/ML Product Line Manager, Harman RedBend ( B2B Automotive) *2021 û 2024*

RedBend OTA is a leader product in the automotive market for cellular updates.
Established the AI/ML domain from scratch. Pioneered the AI/ML domain, developed a strategic roadmap, defined the technologies/data/development processes/roles/responsibilities (R&R).
Launched 4 AI/ML features to beta, including a RAG-based tool, accelerating innovation adoption by major OEMs: PSA, FCA, RNA, TM, GTM, Subaru

Examples for AI/ML solutions:
Predicting the vehicles on which the software update campaign will fail using Machine learning on tabular data. A feature added to the OTA (Over The Air) server. This feature saves a lot of manual post campaign effort and a lot of driversÆ dissatisfactions. Beta stage, planned to be deployed on AWS as a service.
OTA (Over The Air) Client (vehicle side) logs analysis using LLM, accelerating the work of technical support team. Deployed on central internal server, using Streamlit.
OTA (Over The Air) Client (vehicle side) logs analysis using LLM, real-time analysis, predicting a bug or failure. Planned for future.
Optimizing the configuration of the Delta co-product by finding the best configurations between tens of parameters, using Machine Learning, resulting improved results for internal and external customers. Data generated by using the tool in a close loop. Deployed on-perm for internal use as step one, as preparation for external use.
RAG solution, for the 60 PDF files that are part of the OTA product release, allowing a simple UI to answer any question about the product, easing the search for answers both for internal and external customers, using embedding, vector database, ChatGPT Azure. Deployed on internal server using Streamlit the with FastAPI





Founder, Cycles-Trader (B2C Deep-AI Algo-trading) *2019 - 2021*

Founded Cycles-Trader, a B2C Deep-AI algo-trading platform, engineering predictive algorithms and launching an e-commerce website, demonstrating full-stack product development and go-to-market expertise. 

Director of Products & Strategy, mPrest (B2B Utilities, IoT) *2016 - 2019*

mPrest is the provider of Iron-Dome command and control.
Led global transformation of mPrest from on-premise IoT defense projects to a scalable cloud/AI platform, securing $10M in new revenues through strategic partnerships and product innovation.
Vision û implemented the vision defined by the management team û move to global products
Strategy û identified the relevant markets, the relevant major players, the business opportunities using market analysis, finally focused on electric utilities, green energy, smart cities.
Defined a portfolio and created the strategy for new products / target customers / sales strategy 
Product Marketing û market research / competitive analysis / value propositions / unique selling points / GTM / focal point for Gartner
Product Management û ideas validation / business model validation / early market feedback / requirements / demos / MVP / UI-UX / meeting customers
Business Development û lead generation / meetings with prospects and 3rd party
Technology: moving from on-prem to cloud and micro-services

Senior Product Manager, Kramer (B2C, ProAV Video) *2015 - 2016*

Kramer is a dominant leader in ProAV worldwide
Initiated, developed and launched video-over-IP product line, unlocking $100M market opportunity and enabling SaaS transition.

Senior Product Manager, Visonic/Tyco (B2B Smart Home IoT) *2012 - 2015*

Visonic is a leader in home-security products worldwide (Acquired by Tyco)
Initiated and drove cloud-first home automation with mobile-app strategy at Visonic, resulting in $200M in new sales and doubling TAM.

Senior Product Manager, BigBand (B2B Video Management) *2011 - 2012*

BigBand is a leader in Cable TV transmission (Acquired by Arris)
Led the video management application for a $300M project with Verizon, contributing to the sales process with AT&T.

Director of Products, Scopus (B2B Video) *2007 - 2010*

Scopus is a leading video transmission solutions provider (Acquired by  
Developed a new video management application from concept to sales, opening new business opportunities and resulting in $40M in sales in the first year, doubling the company's revenue
Pioneered the systems roadmap, dramatically shortening time-to-market systems delivery
Worked with TV operators T1/T2/T3 worldwide (cable, satellite, terrestrial)

R&D background - Various Technical and Architecture Roles 

Held R&D positions at high-tech companies, including Tecnomatix (Application Engineer), Comverse (System Engineer), Business Layers (Technical PM), and Midbartek (PM + Development Group Manager, 12 developers).

Education

- Data Scientist Bootcamp, NAYA College (2021) - AI/ML and data science methodologies
- MBA, Business and Economics, Harriot Watt, Ramat-Gan (2000)
- BSc Computers and Electronics, Technion, Haifa (1988)

Technical Skills

Gen-AI: chats, AI-Agents, AI-Builders, AI-Code, AI-Designs, AI-Automation, AI-Security
Product Management:áAgile, Scrum, Roadmapping, Stakeholder Management, MVP Development
Product Tech Stack: aha!, Jira, Figma, Miro, IBM Jazz, Confluence, Cursor, Claude.ai, Gen-AI
Product Marketing: Pricing, positioning, marketing collaterals, market research, competitive analysis
Business Development: 3rd Party Cooperations, Lead Generation, Sales Meetings and Presentations
AI/ML:áDeep Learning, Predictive Modeling, Algorithm Development, MLOp, Gen-AI tools.
Programming:áC, Python (Data Science), SQL.
Cloud Platforms:áAWS, Azure, GCP.
Other:áTeam Management, Network/Security/Video/Identity Management.

Articles https://www.linkedin.com/in/alonavramson/recent-activity/articles/ 

Military Service - Captain in Navy, Weapon Systems
